{"tossups": [{"question": "Foreign intervention in this conflict prompted the battles of Outpost Harry and Pork Chop Hill. During this war, Matthew Ridgeway replaced a general who masterminded a decisive landing at Inchon, Douglas MacArthur. A demilitarized zone was created after an armistice was signed, though there has still been no peace treaty to end this war. For ten points, name this 1950s conflict on an Asian peninsula.", "answer": "<b> Korean</b> War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Two weeks before this battle, the invading force made their landing at Pevensey. During this battle, one side\u2019s housecarls made a stand on Senlac Hill until their leader was struck in the eye by an arrow. This battle arose out of a dispute over whom Edward the Confessor named as his successor. The Bayeux Tapestry depicts the death of Harold Godwinson in, for ten points, what battle that confirmed William the Conqueror\u2019s rule over England in 1066?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Hastings</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In June 2017, a set of protective electric barriers nine miles from this lake failed to keep out a silver Asian carp. Northerly Island in this lake was home to Meigs Field, an airport that was shut down in 2003 by Richard Daley. South of Sault Ste. Marie [soo saint marie], the Straits of Mackinac [mack-ih-naw] connect this lake to Lake Huron to the east. For ten points, name this Great Lake on the western shore of its namesake US state.", "answer": "Lake<b> Michigan</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "At Botany Bay, convicts and Aborigines met in what became an English penal colony. For ten points, name this country where, in 1770, James Cook landed near what is now the city of Sydney.", "answer": "<b> Australia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Description acceptable. This event was briefly halted when a nearby patrol forced William Dawes to flee; he subsequently fell off his horse and could not finish his mission. This event\u2019s central participant slipped by the<em> Somerset</em> by boat after Robert Newman had placed two lanterns in the Old North Church. Militia were able to prepare to fight at Lexington and Concord thanks to, for ten points, what event in which a Boston silversmith warned of approaching British soldiers?", "answer": "Paul<b> Revere</b>\u2019s midnight<b> ride</b> (accept elaborations; prompt on partial answers, like \u201cmidnight ride\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This artist sculpted the facade of a memorial for Julius II, including a seated sculpture of Moses with small horns. A sculpture of a Biblical hero by this artist was originally commissioned for the Duomo Cathedral and lacks both a sword and the severed head of a giant, unlike a similar work by Donatello. For ten points, name this Italian artist of a nude marble<em> David</em> and the ceiling frescos of the Sistine Chapel.", "answer": "<b> Michelangelo Buonarroti</b> (accept either or both names)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In 1966, Secretary of State Dean Rusk asked this leader if a recent order applied to American soldiers in his country\u2019s cemeteries. Lester Pearson noted that \u201cCanadians do not need to be liberated\u201d in his criticism of this man\u2019s declaration of \u201cvive le Quebec libre.\u201d This leader signed the Evian Accords, leading to the independence of Algeria. For ten points, name this first president of the Fifth Republic who led Free France in World War II.", "answer": "Charles<b> de Gaulle</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Methods for this activity should satisfy criteria like non-dictatorship and the independence of irrelevant alternatives, according to the 1951 book<em> Social Choice and Individual Values</em>. That book outlines an impossibility theorem that applies when this activity involves three or more distinct alternatives and was written by Kenneth Arrow. Methods for judging this activity include \u201cfirst-past-the-post,\u201d which is criticized for leading to two-party politics. For ten points, name this democratic process in which ballots are cast to make political decisions.", "answer": "<b> voting</b> (or<b> election</b> systems; accept word forms)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {"question": "Name either state.", "answer": "<b> Maine</b> and/or<b> Nebraska</b> (only one needed; if two answers are given, both must be correct to get points)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {"question": "In this country, students were attacked in the Night of the Pencils during Jorge Videla\u2019s presidency. Left-wing Montoneros were killed at the Ezeiza Airport during a rally for a returning leader of this country who had been supported by the<em> descamisados</em>, or \u201cshirtless ones.\u201d In the 1970s and 80s, this country experienced a period of state terrorism called the Dirty War. Evita was the First Lady of, for ten points, what South American country ruled from Buenos Aires?", "answer": "<b> Argentina</b> (or the<b> Argentine</b> Republic)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A gun is brandished directly at this person in a Pulitzer-winning photograph by Robert Jackson. This person married Marina Prusakova during a period of nearly two years that he spent as a factory worker in the Soviet Union. This man shot at and missed Edwin Walker a few months before using the same rifle to fire three shots from the sixth floor of a school book depository in Dallas. For ten points, name this assassin of John F. Kennedy.", "answer": "Lee Harvey<b> Oswald</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In this country, suicide bombers pretending to be journalists used an exploding camera to assassinate Ahmad Shah Massoud. This country\u2019s caves of Tora Bora served as the headquarters of an insurgency. The Northern Alliance was formed to defend this country and received Western support when this country was invaded in Operation Enduring Freedom after 9/11. For ten points, name this country where, in 2001, NATO troops toppled the Taliban government.", "answer": "Islamic Republic of<b> Afghanistan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The third of these people died shortly after giving birth to a son whose betrothal ended the War of the Rough Wooing. The fourth of these people was known as the \u201cKing\u2019s Beloved Sister\u201d because she never consummated her marriage; that woman was Anne of Cleves. Clement VII refused to annul a marriage involving one of these women, leading to the creation of the Anglican Church. Catherine of Aragon was the first of, for ten points, what group of six women married to an English king?", "answer": "<b> wives of Henry VIII</b> (do not prompt on queens of England, as the chronology doesn\u2019t work with \u201cthird\u201d and \u201cfourth\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 1997, Fuzzy Zoeller [zeller] made a racist remark about the food this man would select for the next year\u2019s Champion\u2019s Dinner, a remark echoed in 2013 by Sergio Garcia.</b> <b>This man, who refers to his ethnic background as (+)</b> <b>\u201cCablinasian,\u201d won the 2000 US</b> <b>Open by 15 strokes, the most dominating major championship victory in history. In 1997, he became the (*) </b> youngest and first non-white man to win the Masters. For ten points, name this American athlete with the second-most wins in golf history.", "answer": "Eldrick \u201cTiger\u201d<b> Woods</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "A Board of Governors leads this institution, which oversees twelve regional (*)</b> banks and enacts monetary policy. Janet Yellen currently leads, for ten points, what central banking system of the US that controls interest rates?", "answer": "<b> Federal Reserve</b> System (accept the<b> Fed</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>In 1572 in this city, a man known as \u201cBesme\u201d [BEHM] stabbed an admiral and threw him out a window, where he was then decapitated. Shortly after Margaret of Valois was married in this city, a massacre of (+) Huguenots took place on Saint Bartholomew\u2019s Day. In converting to Catholicism, Henry IV claimed that this city was (*)</b> \u201cwell worth a mass.\u201dFor ten points, name this capital city, the site of much strife during the French Wars of Religion.", "answer": "<b> Paris</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After a failed attempt to revise this document to include impost taxing, frustrated officers began planning the Newburgh Conspiracy. The legislative body created by this document</b> <b>successfully passed the Northwest (+)</b> <b>Ordinance, but many clamored for changes after</b> <b>Shays\u2019 Rebellion, because this document did not grant the (*)</b> federal government authority to levy tax or regulate interstate commerce. For ten points, name this American governing document that preceded the Constitution.", "answer": "<b> Articles of Confederation</b> and Perpetual Union", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This emperor designed a building that looked like a palace, but was a torture chamber whose name translated to \u201cHell-On-Earth.\u201d This \u201cBeloved-of-the-Gods\u201d put down a minor</b> <b>revolt in his empire at Taxila, and he ruled his kingdom from (+)</b> <b>Maghda. This ruler\u2019s</b> <b>sculpture of four-outward facing lions at Sarnath and his 24-spoked \u201cwheel of righteousness\u201dwere designed after he waged a bloody war in (*)</b> Kalinga, after which he converted to Buddhism. For ten points, name this descendant of Chandragupta, a ruler of the Mauryan Empire.", "answer": "<b> Ashoka</b> the Great (or<b> Ashoka</b> Maurya; accept<b> Ashok</b>a or<b> Asoka</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This country was the site of renowned mercenaries, including the bodyguard of the (*)</b> Pope, and hosted John Calvin in the city of Geneva. For ten points, name this Alpine confederacy governed from Bern that is traditionally neutral in European wars.", "answer": "<b> Switzerland</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker! (1) <b>This nation, which conquered the German base of Tsingtao during World War</b> <b>I as part of its alliance with Britain, joined Britain, Italy, and France as permanent</b> <b>members on the League of Nations\u2019 executive council. The (+)</b> <b>Doolittle raids</b> <b>attacked this country. Economic conglomerates called (*)</b><em> zaibatsu</em> were created in, for ten points, what Asian empire that annexed neighboring Korea in 1910 and was led by Hideki Tojo in World War II? ANSWER: Empire of<b> Japan</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}